# **Michael Amar**

1728 east 3rd street, Brooklyn, NY 11223 Cell: 917 438 8346 : mordachiamar@gmail.com

# **Professional Summary**

I am an individual interested in high growth companies specifically the technology sector. I have a diverse work background. I also started as well as worked for a number of interesting companies. I try and improve myself by placing myself in situations where learning is necessary.

# **Experience**

#### Student

March 2013 to Current

## **General Assembly - WDI**

- Learned Full-stack web development for 3 months.
- Studied backend frameworks like Sinatra, Padrino & Rails.
- Studied Frontend Frameworks/Libraries like jQuery, Underscore, Bootstrap,& Foundation.
- Used git as well as Github for version control.
- Utilized API's and Restful technologies.
- Levels of proficiency in HTML5, CSS, Javascript, Ruby, SQL.

### **Product Development Team**

November 2012 to March 2013

Unroll.me - New York, NY

- Helping re-design our site and experience to be more user centric.
- Learning Software Development from self study and the team. Aim to join as a developer here in the future.
- Analysis of data to ensure a lean approach to redesign efforts and new features.

#### **Implementation Team**

January 2012 to November 2012

## DineMarket.com - New York, NY

- Early intern turned employee. Helped implement customers onto our platform.
- Monthly Revenues grew from below \$5,000 to above \$20,000.
- Helped ensure customers needs were met at all times.

## Speaker of the House, CUNY Brooklyn

February 2011 to June 2012

#### CLAS Student Government - Brooklyn, NY

- Ran and won student government elections.
- Represents over 11,000 students as their councilman.

#### **Division Head**

June 2011 to August 2011

# Sephardic Community Center - Brooklyn, NY

- Revitalized ailing sports division in a non-profit day camp.
- Collaborated with key staff to train, lead, and supervise counselors as well as ensure safety and well being of youth.
- Innovated league system to teach sportsmanship and teamwork.
- Lead a team of six employees.

#### **CEO**

## Shabbat Flowers - Brooklyn, NY

- Established and operated a local flower delivery and sales service with 50+ weekly clients.
- Part of proceeds went to charity.
- Investment turned profitable within one month.

### **Private Tutor**

October 2010 to June 2011

Sole Proprietor - New York, NY

Free-lanced as an individual educator; helped a disenfranchised youth regain confidence and ability in all subjects (Bilingual curricula). One child was years behind his grade level in mathematics but eventually passed his Regents examinations.

#### Mentor

September 2010 to June 2013

SBHonline.org - Brooklyn, NY

- Volunteer in Big Brother mentor program.
- Recently Promoted to the programs committee

# **Education**

**Brooklyn College** 2015

Brooklyn, NY

Philosophy, Judaic Studies

# **Professional Affiliations**

New York Tech Meetup - Beta Member